My name is Yinka Oduwole.
When I was growing up in Lagos Nigeria, I never imagined
that one day I would be an alumnus of the most prestigious university in the world.
Positive examples are motivators for success.
My success today I owe to the man, although not my biological father, took me, nurtured me, motivated me,
inspired me, sponsored me and taught me to believe
that I could achieve something far beyond what I could ever dream.
As Prophet T.B. Joshua says, "Broken focus is the real reason men fail".
For many, studying abroad can open the door to distractions and temptations.
What enabled me to maintain my focus, was to always remember the great trust deposited in me.
I never forgot where I am coming from.
As I don my graduation gown and collect my doctorate certificate,
I know that I am doing it not for myself alone, but for the thousands all over the world who are right now
being helped, equipped and trained because of T.B. Joshua and the Emmanuel TV partners.
We are the leaders of tomorrow.
With no sign of pressure on her big day, Yinka gets ready for the ceremony.
She has spent the last four years of her life working, researching, and studying for her PhD
or Doctorate of Philosophy in Engineering Science at Oxford University,
thought by many to be the most prestigious university in the world.
Yinka first heads to Kellogg College, Oxford's largest graduate-only college, where she has been studying.
Hello viewers, thank you so much for following me on this journey.
Today is my graduation.
I am graduating with a PhD in Engineering Science in Oxford University.
I am here in the halls of residence in my college, Kellogg College.
I just want to say a big thanks to Prophet T.B Joshua, my mentor
and Emmanuel TV Partners who have made this journey a success.
I hope you continue to follow me, and thank you so much.
Hello, I'm Elsa Bell and I have the great honour today of being the Dean of Degrees.
This means I help the students on their journey as they graduate.
It's such fun, such a great honour because this is one of the most important days of their life.
We graduate in a very serious and solemn way
but in our hearts, we're cheering for the students like Yinka
who have worked and worked and worked to gain her DPhil.
One of the other glories of today is that families, friends and organisations
all stand by and share in this day of great joy.
So, congratulations to our students, thank you to all their supporters
and we know we are going to have a marvellous time!
Briefing For The Scholars On Their Graduation Day At Kellogg College, Oxford University
The graduates are invited with their family members
to hear the briefing of what they should expect in today's' ceremony.
Briefing For The Scholars On Their Graduation Day At Kellogg College, Oxford University
The Dean of Degrees of Kellogg College, Emeritus Fellow Elsa Bell congratulates the graduates
on their momentous achievement and appreciates those
who made it possible for the students to realize their dream of an Oxford degree.
Briefing For The Scholars On Their Graduation Day At Kellogg College, Oxford University
The briefing over, Yinka walks confidently down the same road
as thousands of other Oxford scholars have done before her.
Many of whom went on to become world leaders and history makers.
Having walked down the streets of Oxford,
the graduates with those accompanying them arrive at the Sheldonian Theatre,
the principal assembly room in the university where all public ceremonies are performed.
Yinka Makes Her Way To The Sheldonian Theatre Where The Graduation Ceremony Will Take Place
The scholars in their academic dress enter a private entrance to the Sheldonian Theatre,
each carrying their graduation robes in a special bag,
each colour signifying the academic level they achieved.
All of which shall be donned or worn at the invitation from the College Council
as their degrees are granted to them.
It's obviously a great day for all of you
to celebrate your academic achievement with your family and friends.
In this wonderful building, the Sheldonian Theatre at the heart of our ancient university;
ancient but still very relevant to the problems of the modern world,
pushing back the frontiers of knowledge.
I hope you've all enjoyed your years at Oxford - quite difficult not to do so, I think.
You'd have to have pretty stunted ambitions and interests not enjoy your time here.
And I hope those of you who come back to continue your studies will also have a great time.
As you know, we regard everybody who has been a member of the university as a continuing member.
A university is a living thing.
Once you're part of our community, you continue to be.
So, I very much hope hat you'll keep in touch with your college and with the university
as your careers develop in the years ahead
I hope you'll go to Alumni events from time to time, even when people like me are speaking at them!
To be serious, we're very proud of you and we know we will be even more proud in the future.
Oxford is a great world-class university.
and one of the ways in which we have defined that over the years
is that we send people into the world who help to make it a better place.
I'm sure that you'll be doing that; you'll have all our support in whatever field of activity you choose
for your own next round of achievements.
THE OXFORD DEGREE CEREMONY
Graduation Ceremony of Dr Yinka Oduwole, Oxford University, UK, Sept 16, 2017
Please be seated.
The degree ceremony for higher degrees starts with the supplication, traditionally made in Latin
by the senior proctor for the candidates to be admitted to their respective degrees.
Before we begin the degree day itself, I want to say just a few words, words of congratulations.
This is of course a proud moment for you all - for you, your families, friends and supporters.
A moment of exceptional pleasure, to be savoured at length
and preserved photographically for posterity.
The degree day is certainly the happiest of the ceremonies in the university calender.
Unlike the great burst of relief that everyone feels after examinations,
this a time to recognize and mark formally the personal achievement of gaining a degree.
We shall see conferred here today quite a range of different degrees
from Bachelor of Arts to Doctorates.
But they all have this in common:
They are all the product of a sustained effort, the application of the mind to complex problems
and a determination to overcome difficulties.
Oxford is one of a mere handful of great international universities in the world.
Our entry requirements are exacting; our courses are demanding;
our research programmes are uncompromising.
The opportunities are great in Oxford with its special qualities, its international mix
and the close involvement of academics in the work of students.
But the challenges are great also.
Oxford is not a place, nor does it want to be where a student may rely on being told what to think.
So, it's not easy to get any sort of degree here.
Those who teach and research in Oxford know that and they would want me to say to you
on their behalf that the degree you received today is indeed a considerable
personal achievement and that you are right to take pride in it.
In fact, of course, others have contributed to the outcome being recognised here.
I want most particularly to welcome the families and friends whom I see with us.
The fact that you are here testifies to your support of
and commitment to one of the people in front of me.
Those who study need support and encouragement.
They need timely comfort and unaffected approval from those closest to them.
For all of you, support has meant financial sacrifice
and perhaps the rearrangement of plans.
So, I do want to recognize that the success we celebrate today also belongs to you.
I think that the degrees we are giving here represent two things:
First, they certify that a number of specific skills have been acquired and tested.
Indeed the formulas that I shall use in a minute's time to confer degrees
essentially refer to them as licenses to do certain things.
Most important however, an Oxford degree reflects our intention to promote some qualities of mind.
to teach people how to learn, how to take charge of their thought
What you know is not as important as what you do with what you know.
The crucial but also the most difficult qualities towards which we try to help our students
are understanding, independence of judgement
These are the qualities which you carry out from here with your degree.
These are the qualities which will sustain you in a life
during which we now know more direct skills will have to be often renewed.
And these are the qualities which a stable and successful society needs
in each successive generation.
This event is very ceremonial and solemn here.
Degree days do not have to be so and in some universities,
they can be quite informal and noisy festivals.
We think that solemn ceremony is proper
because the university is bestowing that which is most precious to it
that which carries the values we proclaim and defend.
We think it is proper because we are paying respect
to those who have earned that precious prize from us.
which is the way we show respect in the university.
The ceremony is also in latin; at first sight, that may appear to you impossibly old-fashioned
Let me persuade you of the contrary.
The university has been in existence for the better part of 800 years.
I'm not speaking simply of the longevity of an institution.
but primarily of the the long continuity of an ideal.
Through shifting circumstances and with varying success,
the university has sought values of intellectual honesty, independence of judgement,
and truth - imperfect though each generation's test of that has proved to be.
with the words with which degrees have always been awarded
The robes that will soon display your degree resemble those of your colleagues,
Thus, latin and robes symbolise two essential things:
First, the perenity of certain necessary values.
and will in future stand to hear these self-same words ad don these self-same robes.
Before I turn to the Registrar to begin the ceremony in latin,
just one more word and that is, congratulations!
Supplicant venerabili congrationi doctorum
These students, who have completed
et magistrorum regentium hi studiosi qui
all that is required by the statutes
compleverunt omnia quae per statuta requiruntur
(except in so far as dispensation has been granted)
(nisi quatenus com eis dispensatum fuerit);
supplicate the venerable congregation of doctors
ut haec sufficiant,
and regent masters that these things may suffice
quo admittantur ad gradum enumeratum.
for admission to the specified degree.
Those Receiving Doctor In Philosophy At The Sept 2017 Graduation Ceremony Oxford University
After the proctor calls the names of the candidates supplicating for the higher degrees,
this part of the proceedings is repeated in English.
and the graduants of Merton College, St. Katherine's College and Kellogg College.
For the degree Doctor of Philosophy, the deans
are presented to the vice chancellor, senior proctor and junior proctor
The scholars step down to the theatre floor and in rows, according to their colleges,
to whom they bow ceremonially before receiving the charge.
Magistri et dominis, vos dabitis fidem
Ladies and gentlemen, you shall swear
ad observandum omnia statuta, privilegia,
to observe all the statutes, privileges,
Magistri et dominis, vos dabitis fidem
Ladies and gentlemen, you shall swear
ad observandum omnia statuta, privilegia,
to observe all the statutes, privileges,
consuentudines libertates istuis Universitatis,
customs and liberties of the University,
quatenus ad vos spectent.
as far as they concern you.
Do fidem.
I swear.
Doctoris in Philosophia
Doctor in Philosophy.
Magistri et domini, ego admitto vos ad gradum
Ladies and gentlemen, I admit them to the degree
Doctoris in Philosophia
Doctor in Philosophy.
all the statutes, privileges, customs and liberties of the University of Oxford.
They take the time-honoured pledge to uphold and observe
The candidates for Doctor of Philosophy degrees leave the theatre
to put on their official graduation robes.
Hae gratiae concessae sunt
These graces have been granted
et sic eas pronuntiamus concessas.
and we so pronounce them granted.
At the cue from the senior proctor, two of the council officials symbolically open the door
of the Sheldonian theatre, and invite the candidates to solemnly bow before the vice chancellor.
Graduation Ceremony of Dr Yinka Oduwole,
Oxford University, UK, Sept 16, 2017
Wearing the blue and red robes, they are admitted one by one to shake the hand of the vice chancellor.
who is the effective CEO of Oxford University.
Graduation Ceremony of Dr Yinka Oduwole,
Oxford University, UK, Sept 16, 2017
Smiling after their years of hard work, the Doctors of Philosophy have earned not only
the respect and applause of their lecturers and peers,
but also admittance into one of the most prestigious academic communities in the world.
Graduation Ceremony of Dr Yinka Oduwole,
Oxford University, UK, Sept 16, 2017
With the official proceedings over, the newly granted degree holders
regally dismount their seats together and file out.
Congratulations, Dr Yinka Oduwole!
Graduation Ceremony of Dr Yinka Oduwole,
Oxford University, UK, Sept 16, 2017
Hello, Viewers! Thank you so much for following me on this journey.
I just finished the graduation ceremony held at The Sheldonian Theatre.
I have just been confirmed a Doctor in Engineering Science.
I'm now known as Dr Yinka Oduwole.
Thank you so much.
My name is Kevin Lee. I just graduated with a Bachelor in Mathematics & Computer Science.
I'm from California.
I feel happy that I got my degree but sad that I'm done with my course.
I feel excited to continue my life with a degree from Oxford.
Keep watching Emmanuel TV!
Hi. My name is Jessica Thorn from Namibia.
I graduated in zoology.
I specialised in climate adaption and the impact on small holders in Nepal, Ghana and Kenya.
I just graduated today. It's been a wonderful ceremony.
It's wonderful to be here with my family to celebrate,
going to such a historic institution with so much diversity and international contributions.
It's being part of a network of people who are very dedicated and have taken a lot of sacrifices
to be able to contribute to a bigger body of thought and continued conversation
about humanitarian issues, about trying to create a more sustainable way of producing food,
to producing a more integrated way of nature and livelihoods.
I am very grateful to be a part of this process.
My name is Dr Jessica Thorn.
I just graduated with a Doctor of Philosophy from Oxford University.
Keep on watching Emmanuel TV!
My name is Edward Still. I'm from Bristol.
I just got my DPhil in Modern Medieval Languages here at Oxford.
It's the pinnacle of my studies so far, so I'm very chuffed and pleased.
It's a great honour.
My name is Zahid. I'm Canadian-born.
I did my undergraduate in Toronto
and then came to Oxford to do a Masters and PhD, both in Neuroscience.
It's been an amazing experience. I've learnt a lot about the research, about the brain.
My particular focus was looking at the cellular molecular basis of learning and memory.
After four years, I was able to discover very interesting rules that govern
how people are able to remember things for long periods of time.
I'm off to do a post-doctoral work in Edinburgh University
and ultimately my goal is to become an academic and a professor of Neuroscience.
My name is Zahid Padamsey, and I graduated today from Oxford University with a DPhil in Neuroscience.
Keep watching Emmanuel TV!
My name is Musaiwale Kamfose, and I graduated today from Oxford University.
After the graduation ceremony, the new graduates and doctors return to their various colleges
to celebrate with friends and family as well as Oxford professors and academics.
One of the most prominent among them is Professor Jeffrey Thomas,
the founder and first president of Kellogg College.
What a pleasure it is to see Yinka graduate, to become one of the very unusual young ladies
who has got a DPhil from the University of Oxford
and I am delighted that she became a member of this college.
I had the great opportunity a few years ago of helping to found what is now Kellogg College.
It was founded precisely to give opportunities to people from the United Kingdom
who wanted to study part-time and to younger folk from all over the world, such as Yinka.
And I have to say that since Yinka has been here, she has been an absolute star.
She's been here four years.
She's joined in everything, very important in the social life of the college
and absolutely brilliant in her academics.
I am delighted to see her moving on to what I am sure will be a glittering career.
So I want to say: Any more folks you have at home like Yinka, please send them to Kellogg College.
We would be delighted to see them all.
Congratulations Yinka! Come back and see us often!
Dr Yinka With Professor Geoffrey Thomas
Founder & First President of Kellogg College, Oxford
And I will shake hands now. Well done.
Thank you.
Brilliant.
My name is Professor Tom Buchanan. I'm the acting President of Kellogg College.
I have been a fellow here since just after the college was set up in 1990.
We are very pleased to honour today the success of all our students
and in particular delighted with the success of the student you've sponsored, Yinka,
in achieving her DPhil.
The college is the largest graduate college in the University of Oxford
and has grown very rapidly since it was set up in 1990.
We have a very marvellous group of students and we are delighted with the success of all of them today.
The acting president of Kellogg College Professor Tom Buchanan presents Dr Yinka
with her official certificate and congratulates her.
My name is Dr Gary Tonge, and we are here in the UK.
Today, we have been celebrating the graduation of Yinka
where she has been admitted as a Doctor of Philosophy in the University of Oxford
which is actually the most prestigious university in the world.
We're very very proud on her behalf and rejoicing along with Emmanuel TV Partners
and Prophet T.B Joshua, who have had the privilege to support her on this amazing journey.
As a PhD myself, I know how much work is involved.
I know how much toil and energy is involved
and now Yinka is no longer a scholar, student.
She's actually someone who is generating her own ideas, her own research.
She's not just studying other people;
she's now admitted to the most prestigious academic community in the world.
We're very, very proud of her.
Hello, I'm Mrs Fiona Tonge.
What can I say? My husband, Dr Gary, has said it all.
It truly has been a privilege to follow Yinka's progress over the years she's been in the UK.
What can we say? All glory goes to God and thanks to Prophet T.B. Joshua
and all the Emmanuel TV Partners for such an amazing sponsorship
of this very, very, hugely talented girl.
- Congratulations, Yinka! A wonderful achievement.
- Thank you.
I just graduated from Oxford University.
I was one of four students that actually got a doctorate degree from Kellogg College.
My degree was in Engineering Science.
I was awarded the degree this afternoon and it was four years
and during the four years, there were lots of challenges
but because of the teaching and mentorship I received from Prophet T.B. Joshua,
today it's a success as you can see and testify to.
I just want to say thank you so much for making this journey a success.
It wouldn't have been possible without your support. Thank you.
I'm just going to show you my name on the programme list.
I was awarded a Doctor of Philosophy in Engineering Science.
My name is here: Dr Olayinka Oduwole. As you can see here, under Kellog College.
It's a PhD in Engineering Science
and at the moment, I'm doing a research fellowship at the University of Surrey
where I'm involved in research and teaching.
Congratulations, Dr Yinka! Cheers!
TT: Juliet Bwalya, 18/08/18
RV: Mel Flowers 21/11/2018